# Curriculum vitae

### PERSONAL INFORMATION S

# Sanjay Chawla

College Green, Dublin, Ireland

**(+353) 899891730** 

sanschawl17

xans\_chawla17@hotmail.com

Skype sans\_chawla17

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Software Analyst and Architect with a combined experience of 5 years and worked with clients in the USA and Finland. I have been involved in the entire lifecycle of product development from requirement gathering sessions to delivering successful software demonstrations and supporting production systems during the cool-down phase. I am a certified Agile practitioner with experience in XP practices and CI/CD pipeline deliveries.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Java
- JavaScript
- Spring Boot
- Spring Web, Spring MVC
- REST API
- Liferay
- SQL
- C, Embedded C

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# 26 Aug 2019-Present

### Master's in Computer Science

EQF level 7

Trinity College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland

Scalable Applications, Distributed Systems, Urban Computing, Knowledge and Data Engineering

#### 1 Jul 2010-1 May 2014

# Bachelor's in Electronics and Telecommunications Engineering

University of Mumbai, Mumbai (India)

Computer Programming, Digital Systems, Microprocessors and Microcontrollers, Electronic Circuits, Computer Networks, Digital Signal Processing

Projects:

Bluetooth Audio Transfer to Headphones (Embedded C) Interactive Railway Timetable Indicator (ARM Programming)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### 19 Jul 2018-2 Aug 2019

# Principal Financial Group, Pune (India)

# Analyst

- Delivered and designed systems for handling Insurance administration
- Compare and analyse different approaches and frameworks to build admin batch applications (Spring vs Java vs IBM, WAS vs Liberty)
- Developed infrastructural Proof of Concept by deploying Tivoli triggered Spring Boot Batch applications on Liberty servers that filled long time demand of multiple business teams.
- Part of Engineering Culture team involved in adopting practices like DoJo, Design Thinking, etc.

# Curriculum vitae

#### 3 Sep 2014–17 Jul 2018

# Accenture Solutions Private Ltd., Pune (India) Application Development Analyst

- As a Full Stack Developer worked on building web services and Portals as per new requirements and change requests
- Optimising code performance and restructuring layered components to reduce coupling

# Software Engineer

- Banking payment and accounting REST API services using Spring MVC
- Development of Liferay portals using HTML, CSS Bootstrap, JQuery and Node JS.
- Integrating release and deployment processes to DevOps for Agile Release Train
- Promoted Agile development practices and improvements across multiple teams

# **Associate Software Engineer**

- Development of Java EE and Spring backend components to connect to DB2 and mainframe batches
- Adopted coding practices like BDD, Pair programming and quality code reviews

#### 1 Jul 2012–15 Aug 2012

## Intern, ThinkLABS Technosolutions Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai (India)

 As an intern, underwent intensive training in ARM programming. Got insight into RISC microcontrollers and their programming, built specific code for LPC2148 microcontroller. Also, underwent training in communication protocols like RS232 and SPI.

## MAJOR IMPACTS AT WORK

#### Automations

- **Selenium JBehave BDD automation** to reduce end-to-end testing need and integrate this step with Jenkins build pipeline. Major savings to manual testing efforts.
- Automating release versioning and maven updates using shell scripts. Saving 6 hours of developer hours per week
- Replaced manual updating of user addresses from web system to Administration database saving 30 hours of work per week
- Test Data Tool a web-based utility to structure and present high-volume data otherwise only accessible through complex SQL calls.

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Honours and awards

- Awarded Rising Star in Q1 2015 by Accenture for my contributions to the project in a short span of joining the team
- Accenture Celebrates Excellence award for the successful delivery of quality solutions
- Worked in Helsinki as an IT specialist to layout the technical infrastructure for upcoming projects.
- Outstanding Performer award winner at Principal